<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

   <properties>
      <title>Installation</title>
      <author email="Christian.Alarcon@jpl.nasa.gov">Christian Alarcon</author>
   </properties>

   <body>
      <!-- The body of the document contains a number of sections -->
      <section name="Installation">

         <!-- Within sections, any XHTML can be used -->
         <p>This document describes how to install and configure the Manager Operator Tool web
            application. The following sections can be found in this document:</p>

         <ul>
            <li><a href="#Necessary_Software">Necessary Software</a></li>
            <li><a href="#Build_Instructions">Build Instructions</a></li>
            <li><a href="#Reset_Instructions">Reset Instructions</a></li>
         </ul>

      </section>
      <section name="Necessary Software">
         <p>The Manager Operator Tool in its current form can function as minimally as just have an
            Apache server (or PHP5 compatible web server) with PHP5 installed. Additionaly, the HORIZON
            "Manager" software must be running at an accesible location to the web server. Please
            see the installation guide for that software if required. No database is required for
            this release, just access to a Manager grails application, Security grails application,
            and the Zookeeper web service module.</p>
         <p>The JQuery 1.4.2 javascript framework is also required for this software to run, but a
            compatible version is supplied in the /js directory. No set up is required for this. </p>
         <p>Additionally, the plugins JQuery-UI 1.8.4 and JQGrid must also be installed in the /js
            directory. Both are also included in this package with no set up required.</p>
      </section>

      <section name="Build Instructions">
         <p>The Manager Operator Tool can be deployed as easily as copying the contents of
            src/main/html to an active web server directory. A standard apache installation defaults
            to /var/www, however this should be changed to a desired location. The directory
            structure must remain intact as it is in the repository. A first time use wizard will
            auto generate the configuration needed for this tool.</p>
         <subsection name="Software Configuration">
            <p>The Manager Operator Tool requires minimal configuration. Upon first load, a wizard
               will appear to auto-generate all necessary configurations and pointers to services.
               Simply supply a valid username/password and the url of a working manager to begin the
               process. The wizard will then retreive the configuration file and place it in the
               "config" directory as "horizondomain.xml". Alternatively, the "horizondomain.xml"
               file may also be hand crafted and inserted manually into the config directory if the
               domain service is not working.</p>
            <img src="../images/op_wizard.jpg" alt="Op Tool Wizard Screenshot"/>
            <p>The tool still has its own configuration file for the different paths of each
               service. Modifying this will not be necessary under normal circumstances. For
               reference, here are their values.</p>
            <ul>
               <li>$OPERATOR_AUTH represents the relative login API call from $OPERATOR_MANAGER_URL.
                  This should only be changed if the Manager software is ever updated with a change
                  in its Manager Operator Tool API.</li>
               <li>$OPERATOR_LIST_GRANULE, $OPERATOR_EDIT_GRANULE, $OPERATOR_DELETE_GRANULE
                  represents the relative granule management API calls from $OPERATOR_MANAGER_URL.
                  This should only be changed if the Manager software is ever updated with a change
                  in its Manager Operator Tool API.</li>
               <li>$OPERATOR_LIST_STORAGE, $OPERATOR_EDIT_GRANULE represents the relative storage
                  management API calls from $OPERATOR_MANAGER_URL. This should only be changed if
                  the Manager software is ever updated with a change in its Manager Operator Tool
                  API.</li>
            </ul>
         </subsection>

      </section>
      <section name="Reset Instructions">
         <p>If desired, the operator tool can be reset to its default state with the wizard upon
            first load by simply deleting the "horizondomain.xml" file located in the config
            directory.</p>
      </section>
   </body>

</document>
