<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

   <properties>
      <title>Operation</title>
      <author email="Christian.Alarcon@jpl.nasa.gov">Christian Alarcon</author>
   </properties>

   <body>
      <!-- The body of the document contains a number of sections -->
      <section name="Operation">

         <!-- Within sections, any XHTML can be used -->
         <p>This document describes how to operate the Manager Operator Tool application. The
            operator tool GUI is an AJAX website built using the {{{http://www.jquery.com}JQuery
            javascript framework}}. This interface allows a user to view and edit various manager
            database values as well as a visual interpretation of jobs being carried out by the
            manager program set. The main categories of functions are seprataed into tabs along the
            top of the application. Each tab serves a separate set of tasks that can be accomplished
            through the tool.</p>

         <ul>
            <li><a href="#Login_Instructions">Login_Instructions</a></li>
            <li><a href="#Overview_Tab">Overview_Tab</a></li>
            <li><a href="#Product/ProductType_Management_Instructions">Product/ProductType
                  Management Instructions</a></li>
            <li><a href="#Storage/Engine_Management_Instructions">Storage/Engine Management
                  Instructions</a></li>
            <li><a href="#Utilities_Instructions">Utilities Instructions</a></li>
         </ul>

      </section>

      <section name="Login Instructions">
         <p>Upon entering the applications URL, the user will be asked to log in with their
            previously assigned username and password. Fill in the proper credentials in the
            appropriate input fields.</p>
         <p>The log in mechanism works off Manager's authentication system. User login and passwords
            are stored in Manager's database so the addition or removal of users should be done by a
            Sys Admin with the proper priviliges. The Bootstrap.groovy file under the Manager grails
            app controls what appears in the database upon Manager boot. User sessions are managed
            by PHP. Please refer to Apache/PHP documentation if any changes are to be made to
            session settings.</p>
      </section>

      <section name="Overview Tab">
         <p>The overview tab is a quick view into the status of all the processes in our system as
            well as a quick view for statiistics captured in our Solr server.</p>
         <img src="../images/op_overview.jpg" alt="Operator Overview tab"/>
         <subsection name="System Status">
            <p>The system status area shows the online/offline status of all the processes in our
               system. This includes all running managers, inventory, zookeeper, and Solr. The
               respective URL's for each process is listed in this box. To refresh the view, scroll
               to the bottom and click "Refresh Status".</p>
         </subsection>
         <subsection name="Summary of Products">
            <p>The summary of products box shows a quick summary of the count of products currently
               in each manager's database and their respective state/lock combos. The tabs will
               autogenerate depending on the configuration file imported. Clicking any state/lock
               values will redirect the user to the appropriate tabs showing the corresponding
               granules with what was clicked.</p>
         </subsection>
         <subsection name="Storage Summary">
            <p>This box shows the current size and percentage used of each storage registered in
               HORIZON. Clicking each storage redirects to the storage/engine management tab.</p>
         </subsection>
         <subsection name="Monthly Ingestion">
            <span style="font-weight:bold;color:red;">NOT INCLUDED IN THIS RELEASE</span>
            <p>This graph shows the number of granules ingested per month. It does not differentiate
               between datasets as this is a total count. This graph retrieves its data from Solr so
               there may be some lag between what is in the inventory's database and what is shown
               here.</p>
         </subsection>
         <subsection name="Products per Product Type">
            <span style="font-weight:bold;color:red;">NOT INCLUDED IN THIS RELEASE</span>
            <p>This pie chart shows a breakdown of how many granules are currently archived per
               dataset and its percentage of the whole. Hovering over each slice gives more
               detail.</p>
         </subsection>
         <subsection name="Priority Overview">
            <p>These tables show three separate way to get visibility into priority queues. "Granule
               Count By Priority" shows a consistently increasing count of archived granules
               organized by priority. To keep a consistently increasing count, only the current
               day's archived granules are counted. "Average Time To Archive" shows the average
               time, from created to archived, of all granules currently in the manager ing_product
               table. "Current Job Count By Storage" shows the number of jobs currently queued for
               each storage by priority. A dynamic number of tables will be generated depending on
               the number of storages available to that particular manager.</p>
         </subsection>
      </section>
      <section name="Product/ProductType Management Instructions">
         <p>The following are instructions for all functions available related to the management of
            product jobs currently in Manager's ing_product table. Please note that the information
            shown here does not reflect current engine jobs, but rather Manager's tracking and
            managing information.</p>
         <subsection name="Paging">
            <p>Product results are displayed in pages (default 10 records per page). The menu below
               the actual grid contains page navigation elements. To skip to a particular page,
               enter the desire page number in the center input box. To advance or go back a single
               page, or go to the first or last page, use the buttons avilable around the center
               input box. All related page and record count information is displayed here as
               well.</p>
         </subsection>
         <subsection name="Searching">
            <p>The input boxes above each column name is the filtering search box. To filter each
               column with a value desired, type the search string in the corresponding input box
               for the desired column. Numeric inputs are registered as exact matches whereas text
               columns search with a "contains this string" logic. Results will be updated as the
               user types. Results may also be sorted in ascending or descending order per column.
               Clicking on a column label at the top will toggle this feature. Column widths may
               also be adjusted by dragging on the edges of the column header's left or right
               borders.</p>
         </subsection>
         <subsection name="Editing and Deleting Products">
            <p>The operator tool allows for the modification or removal or any of the rows shown.
               Select the desired rows by either clicking on the row itself or checking the boxes on
               the left of the row. Multiple rows may be selected or alternatively, checking the box
               on the very top left of the grid selects all the rows currently displayed. Note:
               There is currently no feature to select all rows across all pages at this moment. To
               delete the selected rows, click on the "Delete" button on the bottom left menu. A
               confirmation box will appear. Once confirmed, the rows will be removed from the
               tables. To edit, click the "Edit" button and set the values of "State", "Lock", and
               "Retries" to the desired values. Please refer to the state/lock diagram in the "State
               Table Diagram" tab. These values will be applied across the board to all selected
               rows.</p>
         </subsection>
         <subsection name="Editing Product Type Latency Setting or Priority">
            <p>Similar to editing products, the user can select one or many datasets in the bottom
               section and click edit to change its corresponding latency value or priority
               level.</p>
         </subsection>
      </section>
      <section name="Storage/Engine Management Instructions">
         <p>To view the available storages associated with Manager, click on the "Storage
            Management" tab.</p>
         <subsection name="Viewing Storage Details">
            <p>To open the details box for each storage, click the "View/Edit Details" button for
               the desired storage. A box will appear with extra information about the storage, such
               as ID, protocol, and the amount of storage used, reserved, and marked as a threshold
               in bytes. To close/hide the storage details box, click on the 'x' icon in the upper
               right of the details box or simply click the summary box again to toggle the details
               box off.</p>
         </subsection>
         <subsection name="Editing Storage/Location Information">
            <p>When necessary, the editing of the used, threshold, and reserved values is possible
               by clicking the "Edit" box in the storage details popup. Clicking this will convert
               the appropriate information into text inputs. Modify the inputs to the desired values
               (positive integers only), and click confirm to send the update request to Manager. To
               return to the details box without making any edits and returning the values to their
               original settings, click the "Cancel" button. With the new one storage to many
               location schema, value updates now go to location entries, but are made invisible to
               the user.</p>
         </subsection>
         <subsection name="Controlling an Engine">
            <p>To pause, resume, or shut down and engine, use the buttons on the right side of each
               engine box. The pause symbol represents pausing, play for resuming, and "X" for
               shutting down. Shutting down an engine will actually kill the process and unregister
               itself from zookeeper. This will result in the engine not appearing on the interface
               anymore. To restart a shut down engine, the process must be restarted manually on the
               host that the engine was on.</p>
         </subsection>
         <subsection name="MRF Generation View">
            <p>The TIE version of the operator tool comes with a built-in GUI
               specifically for the MRF generation process. This includes the
               job queue currently on ZooKeeper and all the running generator
               engines. The engine controls remain the same as the ingest engines, but with the added view of what it's currently working on and the last few jobs it has completed.</p>
            <img src="../images/generator1.jpg" alt="generator image"></img>
            <p>The Job queue and the engine job items share the same job details view shown below.</p>
            <img src="../images/generator2.jpg" alt="generator image"></img>
         </subsection>
      </section>
      <section name="Utilities Instructions">
         <p>The utility tab is reserved for tools admin and experienced users can use to manipulate
            the operator tool or even some of the associated processes as well. Currently there is
            only one utility.</p>
         <img src="../images/op_utility.jpg" alt="utility image"/>
         <subsection name="Recreating the configuration file">
            <p>To reecreate the "horizondomain.xml" file, click on the reload button on the utility
               tab. The process will then take the existing login credentials, the current "default"
               manager (decided by which manager was provided in the wizard), and creates and
               updated "horizondomain.xml" file in the config directory.</p>
         </subsection>
      </section>
   </body>
</document>
